(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-21T23:17:27.853322",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
すてきなホリデイ
[Song: Wonderful Holiday]
近づいている...
Drawing closer...
冬の足音
...are the footsteps of winter.
耳を澄ませば...
If you listen closely...
聞こえる鈴の音
...you can hear the sound of bells.
寝ぼけた頭に...
To a half-asleep head...
響く目覚ましを
...the ringing alarm clock...
手探りで止めたあと
...after fumbling to turn it off,
雪の気配
there's a hint of snow.
始まりを告げる
Announcing the beginning
すてきな季節が
of a wonderful season.
happy holidays
what a glorious time of year !
What a glorious time of year!
すやすやと眠る
Sleeping soundly,
子供たちの手に
in the children's hands...
抱かれたテディベアも
...even the teddy bear they hold
もう待ちきれない
can wait no longer.
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year,
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
as if to wash away all the sad things.
さあ パジャマを脱いだら出かけよう
Now, once you take off your pajamas, let's head out.
少しずつ白くなる街路樹を駆け抜けて
Running past the street trees that are gradually turning white.
華やぎ始めた街は急ぎ足
The bustling city streets are full of hurried steps
贈り物決まる頃 黄昏れてゆく
By the time the gifts are chosen, twilight begins to fall
かじかんだ指をママが温めるね
Mama will warm your freezing fingers, won't she?
Happy holidays, happy holidays, what a glorious time of year!
大切なものはみんなそばにある
Everything that's important is right by our side
穏やかな毎日が続く贅沢
The luxury of peaceful days continuing
クリスマスがもうじきやって来る
Christmas will soon be here
うれしさを隠せない犬や猫まで
Even the dogs and cats can't hide their joy
もみの木に灯る明かりをうけて
Bathed in the lights shining on the fir tree
いつもよりやさしそうなパパの目が笑ってる
Papa's eyes, looking gentler than usual, are smiling
クリスマスは誰にでもやって来る
Christmas comes to everyone
もしひとりぼっちでも寂しがらずに
Even if you're all alone, don't feel lonely
心に住むサンタに呼びかけて
Call out to the Santa living in your heart
幼い頃の夢を思い出してごらんよ
Try to remember your childhood dreams
クリスマスが今年もやって来る
Christmas is coming again this year
悲しかった出来事を消し去るように
As if to erase all the sad things that happened
さあパジャマを脱いだら出かけよう
Come on, take off your pajamas and let's go out
少しずつ白くなる街路樹を駆け抜けて
Run past the street trees turning white bit by bit
Happy happy holidays, happy happy holidays
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は 好き！雪！本気Magic
Ah, the city is like a whipped cake, Love! Snow! Serious Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ Woo
The confetti coming from the sky are angels' feathers celebrating the winter festival, woo!
白銀の国へ出かけるの Go Go Go
Heading out to the silver land, Go Go Go!
雪の汽車が街を駆け Choo Choo Choo
The snow train runs through the town, Choo Choo Choo!
絵本みたいな景色を君に見せてあげるから
I'll show you a scenery that looks like a picture book, so
願い込めて呪文さあ唱えて
Make a wish and chant the spell!
ABCDドシラシドシマジカルミラクルクルPop!
A-B-C-D, do-ti-la-ti-do-ti, magical, miracle, curly, Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は 好き！雪！本気Magic
Ah, the city is like a whipped cake, Love! Snow! Serious Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは 冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
The confetti coming from the sky are angels' feathers celebrating the winter festival!
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は 好き！雪！本気Magic
The aurora-colored town lit up, Love! Snow! Serious Magic!
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If only we could stay as children, Dream Land!
Ladies and gentlemen, Welcome to Snow Miko!
ツンと冷たい季節が好き Love Love Love
I love this piercingly cold season, Love Love Love!
アイスも魔法もとけないように ヒューヒューヒュー
So that neither the ice nor the magic melts, whew whew whew!
ずっとこのままじゃダメなの？ やっぱりドキドキしたいな
Is it no good to stay like this forever? I really want to feel my heart flutter!
未来求め呪文今唱えて
Seeking the future, chant the spell now!
1234水金地火木マジカルミラクルクルPop!
1-2-3-4, Mercury-Venus-Earth-Mars-Jupiter, magical, miracle, curly, Pop!
Ah Hopしたウサギのような気分 好き！雪！本気Magic
Ah, I feel like a hopping rabbit, Love! Snow! Serious Magic!
大地がくれる元気得たら 思い通り明日を生きていけるよ
Once we get energy from the earth, we can live tomorrow just as we want!
まぶしい白に染まるハート君に 好き！雪！本気Magic
Giving you my heart dyed in radiant white, Love! Snow! Serious Magic!
大人のふりなんていいじゃん
Who cares about acting like an adult?
I hear that beat from town The cute angel will come down This is my home I'll let you know
NAMARA fantastic!
The snowscape is lyrical The street gonna be magical I'll set you free in my land oh oh oh
今日の寒さも忘れるように (わすれちゃって)
So we can forget today's coldness (forget it all)
悩みだって悩みだって凍らせて
Even my worries, let me freeze my worries...
消せる魔力よ (もうかい)
This magic can erase them! (One more time!)
ABCDドシシララシシマジカルミラクルクルPop!
A-B-C-D Do-Si-Si-La-La-Si-Si magical miracle-cle Pop!
Ah Whipしたケーキのような街は
Ah, this town looks like a whipped cake
好き！雪！本気 Magic
Love! Snow! Serious Magic!
空がくれるコンフェッティは
The confetti falling from the sky is...
冬のフェスタ祝う天使の羽よ
...the wings of angels celebrating the winter festival
Light Upしたオーロラ色の街は
This lit-up, aurora-colored town is...
好き！雪！本気 Magic
Love! Snow! Serious Magic!
子供でいられたら Dream Land
If we could stay children, it'd be a Dream Land!
いいじゃん！
That's great!
君の前では私
In front of you, I want to...
らしくいていいよね？
...be myself, is that okay?
弱気で流したジングル
A jingle weakly playing...
いつもドキドキだね 第一声
My first words are always nerve-wracking
にゃっはろ〜！
Nyahallo~!
震えた声も ノートの文字も
My trembling voice and the words in my notebook
みんなみんな手繋いで go！
Let's all hold hands and go!
変わってるねって (そーなんだ)
"You're a bit weird" (Is that so?)
なんて言ったの？ (まぁいっか)
"What did you say?" (Oh well)
飲み込んじゃってきた言葉も
Even the words I ended up swallowing...
君と笑った声で ほら咲いて
...look, they blossom with our laughing voices!
ばんざい！
Hooray!
こんな私でも
Even for someone like me...
モーマンタイ！
No problem!
好きだなって ねえほんと？
I like you. Hey, really?
冗談？ わかりそう？ どっち？ わかんない！
A joke? Do you get it? Which is it? I don't know!
さくらんぼメッセージ 受け取って
Accept my Cherry Message...
いっせーのーせ で！
...on the count of three!
きっともっとキュンとしちゃうような
It'll surely make your heart throb even more!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Cherry Message...
つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで！
...packed tightly into a bud!
君の前では私
In front of you, I want to...
らしくいていいよね？
...be myself, is that okay?
なんて返そっか (没頭！)
How should I reply? (Absorbed!)
頭が (フットー！)
My head is (Boiling!)
素真が (モットー！)
Being honest is my (Motto!)
ゲームの中なら (get you！)
If it's inside a game, (Get you!)
攻略 (しょっちゅう？)
Clearing it (Frequently?)
百発 (百中！) なのにね
A hundred percent (Bullseye!), yet in reality...
どったんばったん踊ったんなら 悩んじゃったってブギウギ！
If we dance up and down, even worrying is boogie-woogie!
ハート ずっきゅんばっきゅん
My heart goes thump-thump!
スタートボタン 押せるかな？
Can I press the start button?
ちゃんと言ったっけ？ (どーだっけ？)
Did I say it properly? (Did I?)
言わなきゃよかった？ (そーだっけ)
Should I have not said it? (Is that so?)
抑え込んじゃって また焼きもち
Suppressing it makes me jealous again
あー私なんて しゃがみそうになって
Ah, someone like me feels like crouching down...
これが私だもん
But this is who I am!
大賛成！
Strongly agree!
行くよって ほらこっち！
Here I go, look this way!
右？曲がっちゃう？
Right? Turning?
左？迷っちゃう！
Left? Getting lost!
まっすぐ！
Straight ahead!
さくらんぼメッセージ 春めいて舞って飛び立って！
Cherry Message, feeling like spring, dancing and flying away!
そっとじっとしゅんとしちゃう日も
Even on days when I quietly feel down...
さくらんぼメッセージ
Cherry Message...
瞳に ぱっと 映るよ！
...will suddenly reflect in your eyes!
背中を押して メロディー
Pushing my back, melody...
好きでいていいよね？
...it's okay to keep liking you, right?
誰かじゃなくて 君がいいよって...
Not anyone else, I want it to be you!
絶対！
Absolutely!
何度でも言うよ
I'll say it as many times as it takes!
もう一回！
One more time!
好きだなって ねえほんと？
I like you. Hey, really?
冗談？ わかりそう？ どっち？ わかんない！ 本当だー！
A joke? Do you get it? Which is it? I don't know! It's true!
さくらんぼメッセージ 受け取って
Accept my Cherry Message...
いっせーのーせ で！
...on the count of three!
きっともっとキュンとしちゃうような
It'll surely make your heart throb even more!
さくらんぼメッセージ
Cherry Message...
つぼみにぎゅっと詰め込んで！
...packed tightly into a bud!
君の前では私
In front of you, I want to...
らしくいていいよね？
...be myself, is that okay?
好きでいていいよね
It's okay to keep loving you, right?
はーい！にゃっはろ〜！
Hi! Nyahallo~!
エリート巫女アイドルクリスマス、さくらみこ新衣装お披露目ライブに来てくれてどうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to the Elite Miko Idol Christmas, Sakura Miko New Outfit Reveal Live!
そしてみんな、メリークリスマス！イェーイ！
And everyone, Merry Christmas! Yay!
えー本日クリスマスはなんと、みこちゃんのホロライブ加入記念日でもあります！
Also, today on Christmas is actually the anniversary of Miko-chan joining Hololive!
おめでとう！ありがとう！ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you! Thank you!
そして、お披露目したこちらの衣装は、200万人記念で作らせていただいた、新衣装のルームウェア... ルームウェア衣装となっております！
And this outfit that I just revealed is the new room wear... room wear outfit that we made to celebrate reaching 2 million subscribers!
かわいいでしょう？
Isn't it cute?
あのね、いつも新衣装ね悩んでるんですけど、
You see, I always worry about my new outfits,
作りたいなってずっと想ってたんだけど、なかなかね、
and I've wanted to make this for a long time, but...
踏み切れなかった、このルームウェアをね、200万人記念で作らせてもらいました！
I couldn't take the plunge. But I made this loungewear for my 2M milestone!
いいアイディアだったよね、これね？
It was a great idea, wasn't it?
そして、ちょっと見ていただくんですけど、
And now, take a look at this!
こちら！じゃじゃーん！ヘアバンド！
Here it is! Ta-da! A hairband!
これ、みこぴーのヘアバンドになってます。
This is a Mikopi hairband.
ちょっとふわふわしてる、かわいいし、
It's nice and fluffy, and so cute!
このピンもいっぱい付いてて、イヤリングもかわいくって、
It has lots of hairpins, and the earrings are super cute too!
あと、このさくらんぼになってるんですよ、めっちゃネックレス、かわいい。
Also, the necklace has cherries! It's so cute.
で、このね、ダボっとした、ニットに、
And this baggy knit cardigan...
ちょっとセクシーなね、ちょっとセクシーな、
...and some slightly sexy... slightly sexy...
ルームウェアになってます。
...loungewear!
あの、ちょっとね、みこちゃんはおへそ見せないんですけど、
I don't usually show my belly button...
おへそがね、見えます！
...but now, you can see it!
ちょっと、あの、若干、
It's just, well...
ね、寒くなるとね、食べたくなって、若干ぷにってる気はしなくもないけど、
when it gets cold, I eat more, so it might be a little soft...
まあ、まあ、まあ、まあ、気にしたほうは負けですからね。
But hey, you lose if you worry about it.
大丈夫、健康的な範囲だからね、大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's fine, it's a healthy level. It's totally fine!
ということで、
And so...
あのね、隅々までちょっと見ていただきたいんですが、
I want you to look at every detail, but...
もっとね、見ていただきたいところがあります。
...there's something else I want you to see!
見て！この、お部屋！かわいい！
Look at this room! It's so cute!
本日のライブはなんとトリプルコーンさんにね、製作を、あの、お願いさせていただきまして、作ってます！本当にどうもありがとうございます！めっちゃかわいいの！
This stage for today's live was made by Triple Cone! Thank you so much! It's incredibly cute!
もう本当にね、みこぴーとかね、このソファーとかね、めちゃくちゃ細かく作っていただいております。
They really did an amazing job with the Mikopi plushies, the sofa, and all the details.
この後もね、ちょっとね、びっくりする、ギミックとかもありますので、お楽しみに！
There are some surprising gimmicks coming up later too, so look forward to them!
じゃあね、
Now then...
あ、そうだ、ハッシュタグだ、ハッシュタグ。ハッシュタグは、
Oh, right! The hashtag! The hashtag is...
えー、こちら、あの、さくらみこ新衣装クリスマスライブでね、応援してください。スクショもたくさん撮ってね。
this one! Please support me using #さくらみこ新衣装XmasLIVE! Take lots of screenshots too!
ちょっとスクショタイム。
Let's do a quick screenshot time.
はい、
Okay...
キラーン。
Sparkle!
あ、かわいい！
Ah, so cute!
So cute!
あ、かわいい！かわいい！
So cute! Cute!
あ、かわいい！
So cute!
はい、かわいい！
Yes, cute!
ということでね、みんなたくさん撮ったよね？
I'm sure you all took plenty, right?
はい、お願いします！
Please post them!
そして、なんと、最後に重大告知もありますので、最後までぜひ、お見逃しなく！ありがとう！よろしくね。
And we also have a major announcement at the end, so please don't miss it! Thank you! Enjoy the show.
それでは、次の曲行きますか？
Well then, shall we move on to the next song?
こちらにね、移動させていただきまして、はい。
Let me move over here... Okay.
それでは、次の曲、行くぞ！
And now, here is the next song!
半端ないっぱっ ぱっぱらっ ぱっぱらっぱ (はい)
Unbelievable-pa, pa-ppara, pa-pparappa! (Yes!)
限界突破っ ぱっぱらっ ぱっぱらっぱ (はい)
Break your limits-pa, pa-ppara, pa-pparappa! (Yes!)
毎日半端ないっぱっ ぱっぱらっ ぱっぱらっぱ
Every day is unbelievable-pa, pa-ppara, pa-pparappa!
限界突破っ ぱっぱらっ ぱっぱらっぱ（ヘイ）
Break your limits-pa, pa-ppara, pa-pparappa!
最適温度 uh 過ぎるゴースト
Perfect temperature, uh, passing ghost.
八百万の 嫌な外的要素
Countless unpleasant external factors.
「何気ない」と 超あっけらかんと
Acting completely unconcerned, saying "It's nothing,"
悪気もなく邪魔するどっかの誰かさんにバイバイ
say bye-bye to whoever is getting in the way with no ill intent.
自分時間 堕落タイム確保 17時〜9時は死守マスト
Securing my me-time and laziness time; 5 PM to 9 AM is a must-defend!
さらに愛や恋や甘いも忘れずに とどのつまり
Also, don't forget love, romance, and sweets. In the end,...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
I'm warning you that overworking is strictly prohibited.
ねえ楽して 苦なくして 生きてくって難しいな
Hey, it's hard to live an easy life with no pain.
だって「安定」「裏技」「一夜漬け」 甘い蜜には罠がある
After all, in "stability," "shortcuts," and "cramming," sweet honey has its traps.
眠くなったら寝る局
When I get sleepy, I sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up after noon.
遊びたくて遊ぶ
I play because I want to play.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
When I'm hungry, I eat.
嬉しかったら笑う
When I'm happy, I laugh.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
And when I'm sad, isn't it okay to cry?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of tomorrow's me, I'll somehow do my best today.
明日もう頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
I'll do my best so that I don't have to do my best tomorrow!
怠惰じゃないや これ多分そうだ なんやでやることやっています！
It's not laziness. Yeah, that's probably it. I'm doing what needs to be done!
WHAT? & BUT! 誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
What? & But! I don't really care even if nobody knows about it.
私には私のマイルール 明日楽するためにはハイチーズ！
I have my own rules. To make tomorrow easy, say cheese!
意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースのある毎日を生きてたいのです
Actually, I just want to live every day like this with love and peace.
Don't be Don't be Don't be shy
ドキドキとしたい
I want to feel my heart throb.
Let Let Let me shine
明日天気になれ
I hope it'll be sunny tomorrow.
To To To be excite
To, to, to be excited!
心もっと踊りたい
I want my heart to dance even more.
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday 木金土日月
Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thu, Fri, Sat, Sun, Mon.
辛くなったら歌う
When things get tough, I sing.
むかついたら愚痴る
When I'm annoyed, I complain.
やりたいようにやる
I'll do things the way I want.
それができたら苦労しないわ<
If it were that easy, I wouldn't have any worries.
常に一喜一憂
Constantly swinging between joy and sorrow.
してりゃ何様あろうと勝たんだから
As long as I do, no matter what happens, I'll win.
適度にセーブしリスクは回避しつつで　まぁ頑張るのさ
Saving moderately while avoiding risks, well, I'll do my best.
適当にとまでは言うまいが　まぁ頑張るのさ
I won't go so far as to say slacking off, but well, I'll do my best.
夢の中では…
In my dreams...
ずっとぐーたらしてやるんだ
I'll laze around forever.
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなく明日の私のため (Fight)
Not for someone else, but for the me of tomorrow (Fight)
楽するために苦しいことも乗り越えちゃうんだからね (Fight)
Because I'll even overcome painful things just to take it easy (Fight)
やりたくないことやらないためにやりたくないことやれ (Fight)
Do what you don't want to do so you don't have to do what you don't want to do (Fight)
あれ？これって結果頑張れてる？私とっても偉いじゃないか！
Huh? Does this mean I'm actually doing my best? Aren't I super amazing?!
自分時間　堕落タイム確保 17時～9時は死守マスト
Securing my own lazy time, protecting 5 PM to 9 AM is an absolute must
さらに愛や恋や甘いも忘れずに
And don't forget love, romance, and sweet things too
とどのつまり
In the end...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
Overworking is strictly prohibited, I'm even warning you about it
ねぇ楽して苦なく生きてくって難しいな
Hey, living easily without any suffering is quite difficult, isn't it?
だって「安定」「裏技」「一夜漬け」甘い蜜には罠がある
Because behind "stability," "cheats," and "cramming," sweet honey has its traps
眠くなったら寝る
If I get sleepy, I'll sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
I'll wake up past noon.
遊びたくて遊ぶ
I'll play because I want to.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
If I get hungry, I'll eat.
嬉しかったら笑う
If I'm happy, I'll laugh.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
If I'm sad, isn't it okay to cry?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of tomorrow's me, I'll somehow do my best today too
明日も頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
I'll do my best so that I don't have to do my best tomorrow
半端ないぱっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱら
Incredible papparapparapparappara
限界突破っぱらっぱらっぱらっぱら
Breaking limits papparapparapparappara
毎日半端ないぱっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱら
Every day is incredible papparapparapparappara
限界突破っぱらっぱらっぱらっぱら
Breaking limits papparapparapparappara
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり“XX”してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know, you know. I know you're doing "XX" all by yourself.
ピクンピクン震えてさ　声もダダ漏れなんだわ
You're trembling and twitching, and your voice is leaking out completely.
正直に言っちゃえよ　バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ　効いてんの？
Just say it honestly, it's already exposed anyway, just say it. Is it working?
普通普通恥ずかしい？　みんな隠しているだけ
Is it normal, normal to be embarrassed? Everyone is just hiding it.
モニタリング
[Song: Monitoring]
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり“涙”してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know, you know. I know you're crying all by yourself.
グスングスン凹んでさ　弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sobbing and feeling down, singing your complaints alone in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース　もっと泣いたって
We're on a course together until morning comes, so even if you cry more...
何度だって受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you as many times as it takes.
もう我慢しないでいっぱい出しねね MWAH!
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out, okay? MWAH!
お願い　きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
慰めさせてシェイクシェイク　愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, shake shake, with the talent of love.
泣いてくれなきゃ　枯れてしまう　濡れていたい
If you don't cry for me, I'll wither away... I want to stay wet.
ねえいいでしょう？　舐め取って飲み干したいんだってば
Hey, is it okay? I'm telling you, I want to lick it up and drink it dry.
MWAH!
お願い　きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
頼り散らしてシックラブ　なんて最高ね
Relying on each other for this sick love, isn't it just the best?
分けてくれなきゃ　君の“痛い”感じていたい
If you don't share it, I want to feel your "pain."
ねえいいでしょう？　吸い取って救いたいんだってば
Hey, is it okay? I'm telling you, I want to suck it out and save you.
見たい…
I want to see...
見たい　きみの中
I want to see inside of you.
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり悔しがってんの知ってるよ
Hey, I know, you know. I know you're feeling frustrated all by yourself.
ズキュンズキュン高まるじゃん　きみを推すことをやめない
My heart is throbbing more and more, I won't stop supporting you.
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみはできる子知ってるよ
Hey, I know, you know. I know you're a capable child.
つらい時は弱いぐらいで丁度良い　あたしそれでも好きだよ
When times are tough, being a bit weak is just right, I still love you.
MWAH!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
名前を呼んでよいつだって会いに参上
Call my name, I will always show up to see you.
きみはひとりだ だから歌う「ひとりじゃない」
You are alone, and that's why I sing "You are not alone."
もういいでしょう？　ソロプレイはおしまいなんだってば
Isn't it enough already? I'm telling you, solo play is over.
きみが病めるときとも あたし側にいるわ
Even when you are sick, I will be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ　そうよ怖くないのよ
I'm always watching over you, that's right, there's nothing to be afraid of.
MWAH!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
慰めさせてシェイクシェイク　愛の才能で
Let me comfort you, shake shake, with the talent of love.
泣いてくれなきゃ　枯れてしまう　濡れていたい
If you don't cry for me, I'll wither away... I want to stay wet.
ねえいいでしょう？　舐め取って飲み干したいんだってば
Hey, is it okay? I'm telling you, I want to lick it up and drink it dry.
MWAH!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
頼り散らしてシックラブ　なんて最高ね
Relying on each other for this sick love, isn't it just the best?
分けてくれなきゃ　君の“痛い”感じていたい　覗いていたい
If you don't share it, I want to feel your "pain" and peer inside.
吸い取って救いたいんだってば
I'm telling you, I want to suck it out and save you.
ねえあたし知ってるよ きみがひとり“涙”してるの知ってるよ
Hey, I know, you know. I know you're crying all by yourself.
グスングスン凹んでさ　弱音ヒトカラ in the night
Sobbing and feeling down, singing your complaints alone in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース　もっと泣いたって
We're on a course together until morning comes, so even if you cry more...
何度だって受け止めてあげる　もう我慢しないで出してってばさあ
I'll accept you as many times as it takes, so don't hold back anymore, just let it out.
ずぅっといっしょ！
[Song: Zutto Issho!]
充電器を貸して！
Lend me your charger!
またあなたのせいで あたしすり減った
Once again because of you, I'm worn down.
終電見逃して
I missed the last train...
またあたしのせいで 帰れなくなった
...and once again because of me, we can't go home.
繋がっていようね 消耗戦に持ち込んで
Let's stay connected, dragging this into a war of attrition.
お互いに足を引っ張ったアオハル
Our youth where we dragged each other down.
沈殿した思い出でずーっといっしょ！
With sedimented memories, together forever!
参観日にだって 誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
Even on parent-teacher day, I felt like nobody was looking.
散々シニカって 昼の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
Being so cynical, I tried not to expect anything from the daytime city.
そうやって守った孤独さえめちゃくちゃになった
Even the loneliness I protected that way was messed up.
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I always want to die so badly.
こんな顔大事にしたいと思えないもん
There's no way I can cherish a face like this.
共に過ごした日々が
The days we spent together,
ささやかな幸せが
our modest happiness...
かけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
I hope it becomes an irreplaceable trauma.
はなればなれなんて誰かが吐かせたバグだよね？
Being apart is just a bug someone let slip, right?
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you as your life's greatest regret.
Q.大切なものって、なぁに？
Q. What is the most important thing to you?
A.今、失くしたそれ
A. What you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You've gone and made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back now, is there?
健やかなるときも 病めるときも
In sickness and in health...
グロい履歴の中で ずーっといっしょ！
Through our grotesque history, together forever!
もうちょっと普通に 悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
I wanted to feel sad about sad things a bit more normally.
短調のチューンに 感情委託して楽になりたかった
I wanted to entrust my feelings to a minor tune and find peace.
「せいぜい一生懸命に生きてくださいね」
"Please live your life as best as you can."
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない
I always want to die so badly.
あんな歌の言いなりになっていたくないの
I don't want to be at the mercy of a song like that.
あなただけひとりで あたしの目を盗んで
Don't think you can sneak behind my back,
幸せになろうなんて思わないで
and find happiness all on your own.
髪を乾かしてくれた夜から
Ever since the night you dried my hair...
あたしは壊されたんだよ
...I've been completely broken.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you as your life's greatest regret.
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに
Like a ring that can no longer be taken off.
何度もずっとフラッシュバックしている、最低だよ
It keeps flashing back over and over, it's the absolute worst.
一緒に居たときの方が あたし可愛かったなぁ
I was much cuter when we were together.
あなたの一生の後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay with you as your life's greatest regret.
Q.大切なものって、なぁに？
Q. What is the most important thing to you?
A.今、失くしたそれ
A. What you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You've gone and made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back now, is there?
健やかなるときも 病めるときも
In sickness and in health...
他の誰かと眠っていても
...even if you are sleeping with someone else.
お揃いの悪夢でずーっといっしょ！
We'll share the same nightmare, together forever!
天、天、天、天、天、天
Heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven, heaven!
天天天国地獄国
Heaven-Heaven-Heavenly Hell-Hell!
Open Sesame
闇と光の交わる fanatic
A fanatic where darkness and light intersect,
今宵味わう psychedelic
savoring the psychedelic tonight.
踊り絡まり合う zodiac
Zodiac dancing and intertwining,
恋の駆け引きの tie-break
the tie-break of love's tactics.
飾らない存在 ただ気を惹きたい
An unadorned presence, just wanting to attract attention.
夢見心地 触れ合い 惑わせたい
Dreamy feeling, touching, wanting to bewilder.
曖昧 溶けない cocktailは甘い
An ambiguous, undissolving cocktail is sweet.
鮮やかな赤いeye 見つめて限界
Staring into vibrant red eyes, reaching my limit.
月夜に誘われ
Invited by the moonlit night...
天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔が
Angels and devils, angels and devils, angels and devils...
偶(たま)さか接した
...happened to make contact.
天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
Heaven, of hell, heaven, of hell, heaven, of hell...
狭間で出会った
...they met in the threshold.
天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔と 天使と悪魔が
Angels and devils, angels and devils, angels and devils...
集って踊れば
...gathering to dance,
天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 門が開く
the gates of heaven and hell will open.
闇と光の交わる fanatic
A fanatic where darkness and light intersect,
今宵味わう psychedelic
savoring the psychedelic tonight.
踊り絡まり合う zodiac
Zodiac dancing and intertwining,
恋の駆け引きの tie-break
the tie-break of love's tactics.
Dead Alive
Death Death Death
Birth Birth Birth
Dead Alive
Death Death / Birth Birth
Death / Birth
Let's Go
生きた魂を trayに置いて
Place the living soul on the tray.
めくる5枚の card 揺れる炎
Flip five cards, the flickering flames.
先にあなたが raiseしたなら
If you raise first,
もう迷わない glass飲み干して
I won't hesitate anymore, drinking the glass dry.
今夜 All-in 降りない この勝負
Tonight, all-in, I won't fold this match!
いま、天国と地獄をつなぐ門が開いてゆく
Now, the gate connecting heaven and hell is opening.
天使と悪魔、死者と生者が入り乱れ、踊り、笑い
Angels and devils, the dead and the living mingle, dancing and laughing.
すべては混沌の中に飲み込まれてゆく。
Everything is being swallowed into chaos.
それは世界の終焉であり、
It was the end of the world,
新たなる始まりでもあるのだった。
and also a brand new beginning.
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death Death
Birth Birth Birth
Dead Alive Dead Alive
Death Death
Birth Birth
Death Birth Death
天天天天 天国 天
Hea-Hea-Hea-Heaven, Heaven!
天天天天 天国 地獄
Hea-Hea-Hea-Heaven, Hell!
天天天天 天国 天
Hea-Hea-Hea-Heaven, Heaven!
天天天天 天国 地獄
Hea-Hea-Hea-Heaven, Hell!
月夜に誘われ
Lured by the moonlit night,
天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Angels and devils, angels and devils, angels and devils...
偶さか接した
...happened to meet.
天国 地獄の
Heavenly and hellish,
恍惚消えない 果てない moon-night
the ecstasy never fades on this endless moonlit night.
天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
Of heaven and hell, of heaven and hell,
狭間で出会った
meeting in the space between.
天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Angels and devils, angels and devils, angels and devils...
集って踊れば
gather and dance,
天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の 天国 地獄の
heaven and hell, heaven and hell, heaven and hell...
狭間で出会った
meeting in the space between.
天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔と 天使と 悪魔が
Angels and devils, angels and devils, angels and devils...
集って踊れば
gather and dance,
dance dance dance dance
天天天天 天国 天
Hea-Hea-Hea-Heaven, Heaven!
天天天天 天国 地獄
Hea-Hea-Hea-Heaven, Hell!
天天天天 天国 天
Hea-Hea-Hea-Heaven, Heaven!
天天天天 天国 地獄
Hea-Hea-Hea-Heaven, Hell!
ワン、ツー、スリー、フォー！
One, two, three, four!
回想中熱くなりお茶いかが？
Getting worked up in retrospection, how about some tea?
冷静に大人で
Calmly, like an adult...
ハートは君にまだ教えずに
Without showing you my heart yet...
ご相談チラチラと
...casting glances your way for advice.
余裕 身につけて言う「お相手はYou？」
Putting on a cool face and asking, "Is your partner You?"
ドラマのようなことしない女優
Like an actress who doesn't do dramatic things.
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead you perfectly, but...
そのボーダーも〜超えらんないの
I can't even cross that border...
そもそもの話まだ隠して 見つめてる
Still hiding the original story, I'm gazing at you.
Snow halation
[Title: Snow halation]
不思議だね いまの気持ち
It's strange, this feeling right now
空から降ってきたみたい
It seems to have fallen from the sky
特別な季節の色が
The special colors of the season...
ときめきを見せるよ
show me this excitement.
初めて出会った時から
Since the first time we met,
予感に騒ぐ心のMelody
a melody of premonition stirs in my heart.
とめられないとまらない なぜ
It's unstoppable, it won't stop, why?
届けて 切なさには
Deliver this, to this painful yearning...
名前をつけようか "Snow halation"
shall we give it a name? "Snow halation"
想いが重なるまで待てずに
Unable to wait until our feelings overlap,
悔しいけど好きって純情
it's frustrating, but my love is pure.
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
Even hesitating in this slight fever is no good.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
I approve of the courage to dive in, it'll start soon!!
音もなく 気配もなく
Without a sound, without a trace,
静かに運命は変わる
fate quietly changes.
これからの未来に胸の
In the future to come, my chest's...
鼓動が早くなる
heartbeat quickens.
例えば困った時には
For example, when you are in trouble,
すぐ駆けつけて抱きしめたくて
I want to rush to you right away and hold you tight.
どこにいてもどこでも Fly high
No matter where you are, anywhere, Fly high!
急いで いつの間にか
In a hurry, before I knew it,
大きくなりすぎた "True emotion"
my "True emotion" has grown too big.
夢だけ見てる様じゃつらいよ
Just dreaming of you is painful,
恋人は君って言いたい
I want to say that you are my lover.
優しい目が とまどってるイヤだよ
I hate it when your gentle eyes look confused.
このまま一気に愛情 あずけてPlease!!
Please, just entrust your love to me all at once!!
届けて 切なさには
Deliver this, to this painful yearning...
名前をつけようか "Snow halation"
shall we give it a name? "Snow halation"
想いが重なるまで待てずに
Unable to wait until our feelings overlap,
悔しいけど好きって純情
it's frustrating, but my love is pure.
微熱の中 ためらってもダメだね
Even hesitating in this slight fever is no good.
飛び込む勇気に賛成 まもなくStart!!
I approve of the courage to dive in, it'll start soon!!
はーい！みんな楽しんでくれてますかー？
Hi! Is everyone enjoying themselves?
ゲストもね、たくさん来てくださいました！みんなありがとう！
Many guests have also come here today! Thank you, everyone!
そして、見てください！
Also, take a look!
ステージもちょっとね、ぐるっと回転して、外にやってきました！凄くないですか？
The stage rotated a bit, and now we're outside! Isn't that amazing?
ちょっとイルミネーションもね、綺麗でね。
The illuminations are also so beautiful.
もうクリスマスって感じで、ちょっと...もうちょっと若干肌寒い気もしますけどね！
It really feels like Christmas, although... it is a little bit chilly!
もう、凄いきれいだよね！見て！凄い！凄い！
Wow, it's so beautiful! Look! Amazing! Incredible!
はい。どうもありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you very much.
そして、なんと次で最後の曲になるんですが...
And believe it or not, the next song will be the last one, but...
なんと、次の曲は新曲です！わー！
Actually, the next song is a brand-new one! Yay!
みこちゃん、ファーストアルバム以来のね、ソロの新曲となります。
This is Miko's first solo new song since her first album.
えー、ソロライブを経て、みこがまた新たな一歩を踏み出す曲となっております。
After my solo live, this song represents my next new step forward.
それでは、聴いてください。咲き誇れアイドル！
Now, please listen to... "Saki-hokore Idol"!
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I will keep on challenging myself,
君と夢見るんだ
I will dream together with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it so bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇るよ
I will bloom in full glory!
初のイベント 需要無しデフォ
My first event, no demand by default,
そんな私が夢を見ました
That was the me who had a dream.
アイドルという生き方
This lifestyle called being an idol...
憧れて
...I long for it.
「無敵エリート」「笑顔はチート」
"Invincible elite", "My smile is a cheat",
こんな私を見てくれる君
You, who look at this version of me,
好きなとこはどこですか？
What parts of me do you like?
わがままを許して
Please forgive my selfishness.
ステージ経験値 涙滲んで
With stage experience and blurred tears,
それでも絶対負けたくない
Even so, I absolutely don't want to lose.
桜にメッセージ乗せて届け
Deliver my message riding on the cherry blossoms,
愛で溢れますように
I hope it overflows with love.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I will keep on challenging myself,
君と夢見るんだ
I will dream together with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it so bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory!
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end with just delusions,
私らしく桜色 ね♡
In my own style, cherry blossom pink, okay? ♡
磨いたスキル 実力発揮
Showing off my polished skills and abilities,
楽しめる日も増えてきたんだ
The days I can enjoy have been increasing,
アイドルとして生きてる
Living my life as an idol,
君のおかげ
Is all thanks to you.
アホ毛はキュート！勝ち確ルート！
My cowlick is cute! A guaranteed path to victory!
そんな私についてきてよね！
So make sure to keep up with me!
ドジなとこも許されて
With even my clumsy side forgiven,
最強じゃん！
I'm the strongest, right?!
痛いの言いたいのグッと飲み込んで
Swallowing down the painful things I want to say,
笑顔で笑顔増やしたいな
I want to spread more smiles with my smile.
桜前線が君の街に
May the cherry blossom front reach your town,
春を届けるように
And deliver spring to you.
アイドルだけは
Being an idol is the one thing...
譲りたくないんだ
...I don't want to give up.
君に見せたいんだ
I want to show you...
理想へ挑むよ
...as I challenge my ideals.
駆け抜けろ
Run through it!
最高景色見せてあげる
I'll show you the best view ever,
信じていいよ 桜を
You can believe in the cherry blossoms.
さぁ皆で咲かそう
Come on, let's bloom together!
満開のピンクで世界染めて
Staining the world in full-bloom pink!
あぁこの涙はね
Ah, these tears of mine...
悲しい方じゃないから
...aren't because I am sad,
安心して
So please don't worry.
きれいだね
They are beautiful, aren't they?
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol,
挑み続けるんだ
I will keep on challenging myself,
君と夢見るんだ
I will dream together with you.
不器用で悪いか
Is it so bad to be clumsy?
咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory!
妄想だけじゃ終わらせない
I won't let it end with just delusions,
私らしく桜色 ね♡
In my own style, cherry blossom pink, okay? ♡
みんなー！
Everyone!
ピンキーアイドルクリスマス新衣装お披露目ライブを見てくれてどうもありがとう！
Thank you so much for watching my Pinky Idol Christmas New Outfit Reveal Live!
ここで、ここで告知が３つあります！
And now, I have three announcements for you!
まずは、こちら！
First, here is this!
200万人記念、ルームウェア衣装お披露目記念グッズが発売されます！
To celebrate 2 million subscribers, Room Wear Outfit Reveal Celebration Goods will be released!
キービジュアルは、おるだん先生に描いていただきました！
The key visual was drawn by Ordan-sensei!
いつもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much, as always!
イラストのテーマは、お部屋でのんびりしているみこです！
The theme of the illustration is me chilling in my room!
それでは、１つずつ見ていきましょう！
Now, let's look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら！
First, here is this!
リバーシブルブランケット！
The Reversible Blanket!
表には35P、裏にはみこの大きなイラストが描いてあります！
The front features 35P, and the back features a large illustration of me!
丸めて包み込むと、みんなが35Pぬいぐるみになっちゃうよ！
If you roll it up and wrap it, you'll turn into a 35P plushie!
続いて、みことおそろい 35Pヘアバンド！
Next up, the 35P Hair Band matching with Miko!
みこの新衣装とおそろいのヘアバンドです！
It's a hair band matching my new outfit!
毎日使いができるアイテムですので、使ってね！
It's perfect for daily use, so make sure to use it!
次は、みこの愛用35Pマグカップです！
Next is Miko's favorite 35P Mug!
お耳もついてるマグカップなんだよ！
It's a mug that even has ears!
完全に再現できました！
It has been perfectly recreated!
飲み物を入れてもよし、小物入れにするもよし！
You can use it for drinks or as a small accessory holder!
素敵なおうちタイムのおともに使ってね！
Please use it to accompany your wonderful relaxing time at home!
最後は！
And finally!
ルームウェアみこの 35Pぎゅっ♡おねんねぬいぐるみです！
The Room Wear Miko 35P Hug-Tight Sleepy-Time Plushie!
ルームウェア衣装のみこがぬいぐるみになりました！
I've turned into a plushie in my room wear outfit!
みんなも一緒におやすみしようね！
Let's all go to sleep together!
フルセットはこんな感じです！
The full set looks like this!
そしてそして！
And then, and then!
フルセット購入特典は ポストカードです！
The bonus for purchasing the full set is a postcard!
今回は、箔押しの複製サインとメッセージ付きになっております！
This time, it features a foil-stamped printed signature and message!
みんな、ぜひぜひ購入してくださいね！
Everyone, please be sure to buy yours!
告知２つ目は、こちら！
The second announcement is here!
本日初披露した新曲「咲き誇れアイドル」が
The new song premiered today, "Sakihokore Idol"...
本日0時から配信開始！
...starts streaming from midnight tonight!
ファーストソロライブを終えて 次のステージに向かっていく気持ちを
My feelings after my first solo live, heading to the next stage...
HoneyWorksさんに書き下ろしていただきました！
...were written for me by HoneyWorks!
そして、そして、このあと...
And then, after this...
「咲き誇れアイドル」のMVがプレミア公開となります！
The MV for "Sakihokore Idol" will have a premiere!
とっても可愛いので、みんなたくさん聴いて、観てくださいね！
It's super cute, so please listen to it and watch it a lot!
告知３つ目は、こちら！
The third announcement is here!
なんと！さくらみこ×鳴門鯛焼本舗
Incredibly, the Sakura Miko x Naruto Taiyaki Honpo...
コラボが2026年も決定しました！
...collaboration has been confirmed for 2026 too!
なんと、４回目ですよ！
Incredibly, this is our fourth time!
今回の開催期間は、2026年
This time, the event period will run from...
2月20日から3月31日までです！
...February 20 to March 31, 2026!
やったー！
Yay!
本当にね、こんなに長く続いているのは、みんなのおかげでもありますし、
Honestly, that we can keep doing this for so long is thanks to everyone...
鳴門鯛焼本舗さん、本当にありがとうございます！
...and also Naruto Taiyaki Honpo-san, thank you so much!
詳細情報は、後日またXのほうで告知するので、
Detailed information will be announced on X at a later date, so...
楽しみにしていてくださいね！
...please look forward to it!
今日は本当にありがとう、みんな！
Thank you all so much for today!
メリークリスマス！
Merry Christmas!
おつみこでした！バイバーイ！
Thanks for watching! Bye-bye!
めり～くりすます！！ 200万人＆ホロライブカオス記念LIVE♡ どーだったかな？
Merry Christmas!! How did you like the 2 Million & Hololive Chaos Celebration Live?
みんなにいつもありがとうの気持ちをこめて、自主制作LIVE♡ これからも挑み続けるにぇー
A self-produced Live with all my gratitude to you. I'll keep pushing my limits!